Medellin,
scene 25, take 14.
Mark!
Medellin is the story of Pablo Escobar,
one of the greatest outlaws
the world had ever known.
And what attracted you to this project?
What attracted me to this project?
Everything.
It was the script for me. The first time
I read it, I couldn't put it down.
I knew it was a movie,
an exciting movie.
What attracted me to this project?
Well, that's easy.
It was the blood.
4x01 - Welcome to the Jungle
capture:aihua sync:frm
resync: Sixe - swsub.com
/
"Medellin is not a movie. (del vo)
It's life. I's how it is. (del vo)
And I defy anyone to define where life stops and the film starts... (del vo)
Or vice versa." (del vo)
On September the 3rd, 2006,
a completely independently
financed movie crew
set out into the hills of Colombia
to make a movie about one of the most
feared drug lords in history.
A young director,
first-time producer,
and an up-and-coming
movie star all had one goal...
to make something special.
People, people!
I was invited along
to document the ride.
Gather around!
Everyone take a moment.
Breath in the air.
Focus on your surroundings.
This is now your home.
Everything you left behind
is behind you.
Whether it be your wife,
your children,
or your fucking cocker spaniel
named Lucy, none of them matters.
The only thing that matters
is what you can see.
Thank you.
I knew going into this
that Billy was gonna be a handful.
It was my job to handle him
and bring the movie in on budget.
But you have no experience.
No, none, actually.
In fact, four years ago,
I was running a pizza place.
And now they put you in charge
of a $30-million budget?
Only in Hollywood, right?
So how do you know what to do?
I mean, you don't.
You learn on the job. You have to.
And he has this book to help.
He reads it every night.
He keeps it under his pillow.
I have read it about 60 times.
Okay, next scene up,
scene 167...
The storming of Pablo's private prison.
Okay, how many extras will we have?
400, just like the script asked for.
It ain't enough.
It's what the script says.
It needs to be overwhelming.
We need to fill the whole frame.
I'd say another 1,000 will do it.
This is the real Clombian army
we're getting here.
We're getting them cheap.
Can't just throw another 1,000
even at that price.
Turn your motherfucking cell phones off.
Sorry, it's my bad.
There hasn't been any service.
That is the last fucking cell phone
that I wanna hear in the next 45 days
that we spend together.
I'm telling you all right now,
if another cell phone rings
while professional artists
are trying to work,
the responsible
for that distraction
will be dragged into town
and sold as a drug mule.
Does everyone understand
what I'm saying?
It was my bad, okay? But there really
hasn't been any cell phone service.
I think the guy overreacted.
It's just a production meeting.
Not like I blew a shot.
And it's Sunday.
I got to get my football picks in.
I always try to steer my clients away
from working with
inexperienced directors and producers,
because why take a chance?
Vinnie really wanted to do this movie
and there was no stopping him.
But then, when he wanted
to put up his own money,
I thought that was crazy,
because, look,
most movies lose money.
It's my job as a talent representative
to make sure that even if a movie
loses all of its money,
my client still sees all of his.
I've never heard you
mention this problem before.
Makes no difference.
I'm telling you now.
Make sure a crane can
pull right through there. Got it?
- Have you heard it?
- I haven't heard it.
- You don't disagree?
- No, I don't. Do you?
I don't know 'cause I haven't heard
what the problem is.
The problem, suit, is that
we don't have an ending.
I'm sorry, let me correct that.
We have a shitty ending.
An endinthat will take a genius film
that people are loving,
turn them on a dime against us,
and have them walking out of the theater
shaking their fucking heads in disgust.
We're supposed to shoot in three days.
The guy suddenly tells us that
he hates the ending? So what do you do?
Shoot yourself in the head
with a large-caliber bullet.
- I say we shut down for a week.
- No!
We work on the ending...
It'll cost us a little money,
but if we start shooting and then
have to shut down it'll be disastrous.
We'll have something to shoot.
I'm ready to roll.
I don't want to slow down.
- So we're in agreement.
- It's up to E.
Don't worry, suit.
I promise we'll have something to shoot.
I'll write it and it will be brilliant.
I promise, okay?
- Okay.
- All right!
You don't get on a set,
get ready to shoot,
and then ask for rewrites.
Studios do this crap all the time
and they wonder why
they end up with a shit movie.
Movie? You know, I hate
the word "movie."
I don't make movies.
I make films.
You think you're invincible.
Nobody invincible.
Nothing is forever, Mr. Escobar.
I appreciate your position,
Senor de Quintas.
I know you have a job
and a family to provide for.
- Three boys, no?
- Are you threatening me?
Nobody is threatening nobody.
Well, actually, I'm not in the movie.
I'm just sitting in
on the table read as a favor
until they find the real actor.
You see, I'm not available.
I'm on a tv show...
Five Towns.
we had a very successful first season.
And even though I'm on hiatus,
I can't be in the movie.
Contractually I'm not available.
Plus Billy didn't
really offer me anything.
The Cali cartel is a figment
of your imagination, Pablo.
They are ghosts.
When's the next casting session?
If I have to listen to anymore amateurs
I'm gonna slash my wrists.
You want me to try that
with an accent, billy?
- What I would do to that.
- Be professional.
Okay, let's read through this once.
I can read with.
We can leave the kiss out.
Or not.
Why are they in here?
Get them out.
You guys got to go.
Good luck.
Sorry about that.
Okay, let's do this.
- I'm a little bit nervous.
- No, don't be.
- So, what do you think?
- she's fantastic.
I loved her, but we're talking
about the village girl.
And?
- It's just not how I saw her.
- No? How did you see her?
Kind of like Linda Hunt
in The Year of Living Dangerously.
- Really?
- What, you saw Salma Hayek?
I didn't see Salma Hayek
when that girl just read.
Have some fucking imagination, suit.
Makeup, wardrobe.
She can be more plain as you say,
but her essence
is something special.
- Agreed, Vince?
- Yeah, agreed. E?
Okay, makeup.
Any shot she'll have a nude
scene in the film, Bill?
Well, I didn't see it personally,
but what I did believe was
that Billy knew exactly what he wanted.
So it's my job to support him as long
as he got it all done.
And the ending,
has he got that done?
- Not yet.
- So what do you do?
I support him for now.
EIGHT WEEKS LATER (del vo)
October the 27th.
The first day of production had arrived.
The sets were all up.
Why is that door red?
- I thought it popped.
- It popped?
How am I going to see
blood splatter on a red door?
Fuckwad.
Change it.
The actors were all cast.
Show some fucking fire!
As soon as I get this on, vinnie,
we'll put that other eye in for you
and it'll be perfect.
The makeup tests were all done.
- Hey, billy!
- Holy shit.
That can't be vincent chase.
Don't hurt me, Don Pablo! Don't hurt me.
Beautiful job.
Thank you, thank you.
The nose needs to be more thick.
No, that's a very accurate rendering.
He looks just like Pablo.
Thicken it or I'll find someone who can.
And don't put too much on her.
She's perfect as is.
They're ready to shoot.
I need quiet on the set, please.
Of course I'm nervous.
It's only natural.
Who wouldn't be nervous?
- I don't really get nervous.
- Only pussies get nervous.
I'm freaking out a little bit.
It's all on the line on this one
and I have no control.
I don't like that.
Well, whenever you're about to shoot
you get butterflies.
But if you've prepared
and taken care of your instrument,
what can go wrong?
Tony Danza taught me that
when I did a little guest spot.
We're about to roll out of film.
We're gonna roll out of film.
Can I finish my story here?
Scene 16, take one.
How are you, my friend? (del vo)
Parton, I have asked the men and we do not know where the missing kilos gave gone. (del vo)
That is very bad news. (del vo)
Perhaps there has been a mistake. (del vo)
Perhaps you should ask them again. As a favor for me, my friend? (del vo)
Yes, of course. (del vo)
Nino, will you come play a little game with me? (del vo)
Come on, will you ever
doubt the guy again?
That shit looked unbelievable.
- Is this kid a movie star or what?
- Did you like it?
If I don't get a little something
in this movie, I'm gonna kill myself.
I guess he likes.
There he is!
The auteur extraordinaire.
Awesome, Billy.
Bravo, Billy.
Bravo.
What's wrong?
- I hate it.
- You hate it?
- Why? It looks great.
It looks like shit.
Like a hallmark hall of fame movie.
Hey, I did a couple
good hallmark hall of fame movies.
Over lit, man.
Dripping in shit.
You jammed that D.P.
down my throat,
and this is what happens
when I get jammed.
- You picked the D.P.
- Off your list, suit.
Your budget fucking list.
You go budget,
you get a budget-ass look.
- I swear it looks great.
- Vince, I love you,
but I swear it don't.
It looks like shit.
I feel like crying,
I hate it so much. I hate it!
- Here comes Sven. Chill out.
- I hate it, I hate it.
- Hey!
- Enough.
We loving life, huh?
I hate it! I hate it!
I fucking hate it!
Your filters make it look like
someone came on the lens.
- Get off of him.
- You big fucking Scandinavian pussy!
I thought it looked great,
but I'm not a cinematographer.
If billy thought that
it could look better,I believed him.
I believed him too.
But still, we have a budget
and I wouldn't have
let him fire the guy. But I had no say.
After Billy humiliated him he quit.
That always a good sign, right?
When the director starts offing people.
Yeah, big fucking deal.
I decided to shoot the thing myself,
save us some money.
You're fearful.
Like this is the most feared man
in Colombia, right?
But you know that
he lusts after you.
But I'm only selling bananas.
- Why aren't we shooting?
- I just act, kid.
What the fuck is going on?
I think your director's got a crush.
Don't burst his bubble,
but she's been eyeing me for days.
Why aren't we shooting?
- The light's not right.
- When's it going to be right?
When the clouds move.
When's that going to be?
I'm a filmmaker, suit,
not a fucking weather man.
- I'll let you guys talk.
- No, wait...
So what do you want to do?
What I've been doing...
Waiting.
We literally wait two days
for the guy to shoot.
And when he finally does,
suddenly he says,
"no one sees any more dailies."
Nobody comes in here!
You know, I'm not going to be judged
on my work by fucking novices.
We may have snuck a peak.
When billy's right,
he's right.
It looked sick.
Someone just in here?
So is Billy doubting himself?
Nah, Billy never doubts himself.
But something was wrong.
I only have a couple of scenes
in the movie... film.
So I don't understand why the director
wants to eat all his meals with me.
And cut!
That is beautiful.
That is beautiful. Print it!
And everyone else...
Everyone else,
learn from it.
I am so pleased that
you're doing my film.
I see real star quality in you.
You're very Sophia Loren,
except not Italian.
You comprende?
Vince, guys, come join us.
You mind?
Why would I mind?
Hi there.
How you doing?
So, Billy, any word on the new ending?
No.
When a director falls
for an actor on set, all bets are off.
When he doesn't get her,
bet you have a problem.
When someone else gets her,
bet the house.
I nailed one of my directors
on Melrose place.
That was the year
they threw me off, actually.
You think that
might've been the reason?
I don't know.
I never really thought about that.
Why are you hovering
around down there?
We got to talk about the ending.
- We do?
- Yeah, we do.
How would you and me talking
about the ending help?
Because time is running short.
I don't have anything yet, suit,
but stuff is percolating.
I don't have time for percolating.
I need pages to produce. You promised.
Is something else wrong?
Does it look like something's wrong?
Everyone listen up,
I have something very important to say.
Sex kills.
It kills creativity,
it kills artistry.
It kills a film set.
There will be no sex here...
Not on my film set.
I hope that I've made myself clear.
- The ending, Billy.
- Percolating, suit.
Percolating.
I am not having sex with her.
- You sure?
- Pretty sure.
If I don't get a part in this movie
I can have sex with her, technically,
without offending Billy, right?
Yeah, but you may offend
all the Colombians
who would be sickened by the thought.
- Walsh is getting obsessed.
- You think?
I don't care, but he's not writing.
What do you want me to do?
Don't fuck her, for one.
Seriously.
I can still fuck her, right?
Yeah. Drama, if you
can get her, go for it.
Oh, a challenge.
I love it.
You are the most powerfull man in Columbia. (del vo)
But I am nothing without love. (del vo)
I'm scared of you. (del vo)
You needn't be. (del vo)
- Cut!
- What's the problem this time, Billy?
It sucked.
15 takes?
I don't get it.
Would you please tell Mr. Chase that
I want some fucking passion out of him?
- You don't want to tell him?
- I'd rather not.
He wants some passion out of you.
- He's not talking to me now?
- I guess not.
Hey. Let's walk.
- What's the problem?
- There's no problem
Billy, I'm not fucking her.
Swear on it, Vince.
Swear on your mother's life.
I just told you I'm not.
- Then who is?
- I have no idea if anyone is.
Vinnie, man, she told me
she wanted to be friends.
Show me the girl who wants to be friend,
I'll show you the guy who's fucking her.
Well, it ain't me.
So can we go back to work?
Yeah, Vin,
go back to work.
And will you write the ending?
Yes, I will.
He hasn't written shit.
And when we're not shooting
all he does is sit in the bar and sulk.
By thursday, we'll have shot
everything written,
my greatest fear will be realized
and we're gonna have to shut down.
- So, you're starting to panic?
- I'm way past panic.
- Get me Stephen Gaghan.
- Stephen Gaghan?
Yeah. You heard of him?
He wrote "Traffic."
- I know who he is.
- He's a good writer.
- It's a two-week job, tops.
- Why can't you write it?
Rumors already started
about D.P.'s being fired,
production delays, et cetera.
But now they want an academy
award winner to do the rewrites?
Ridiculous.
I told him he'd never do it.
Yeah, I know stephen...
From the brentwood country mart.
Guy loves me.
He'll do it.
Stephen Gaghan's going to cost us
over 200 grand a week.
- So?
- So we can't afford it.
What we can't afford
is not to have an ending.
Figure it out, suit.
This guy's going to
call me suit one too many times,
I'm gonna knock
his fucking teeth out of his mouth.
I called Ari
personally and asked him
if he'd call our financier
and try and get us a little more money.
I told Vince,
"ha ha ha."
our financier
already had enough problems,
you know what I'm saying?
Well, what happened was
I was on my way to
the airport in los angeles
when I was pulled over
and the officer found some cocaine.
Well, it was a lot of cocaine.
Actually.
You're probably asking yourself
why on earth was I bringing cocaine
to Colombia.
Well, truthfully, I wasn't.
As it turns out it was an old bag that
had been lying in my trunk for years.
I had just completely
forgotten about it.
In either case, the judge
didn't really buy that.
Meanwhile, my passport has been taken
away while I await trial.
- My bank accounts were frozen.
- Fuck you, man!
And there's no more money just now.
So I can only pray that the 30 mil
I sunk into this thing
isn't going down some
Colombian drain. Right?
'cause there's, you know,
no suicide watch here.
You know what I mean?
Vince, we can't afford Gaghan.
We've got to get a list
of cheaper writers.
He'll have to go for it.
Don't use the word cheap.
I'm heading to makeup,
see you on set. Hey, be firm.
Have I not been?
Have I not been firm?
What's going on?
He's interrogating the crew to find out
who's been with his girl.
- Fuck you.
- No, fuck you.
I'm going to ask you
one time, chochito.
And if I find out you're lying to me,
I'm not going to be happy.
You understand what I'm saying?
I do, Billy, I do.
And I'm not lying.
I swear.
I never touched her.
Never.
Next.
What's up, suit?
- We need to talk, now.
- No, I'm busy.
Get your ass up and walk with me
right now, or as god as my witness,
I will send you packing today
and I will finish this movie without you.
Who's going to direct, Turtle?
I directed a couple shorts.
What you're making
such a big deal about?
You don't know what?
You convince us we need a new ending,
and while I'm trying
to make that happen,
you're interrogating the crew
about this girl?
I need to know who's fucking her.
- We need an ending.
- And I need Gaghan.
You can't have him, but I've got a list
of other writers you can look over.
What, some cheap piece-of-shit hacks?
I know in my heart
that Gaghan is the one guy
who can get us to
where we need to be.
You're supposed to be that guy,
we have no more money and no way
of getting any more.
- I'll get rid of the extra army guys.
- Not enough.
And lose the Bogata
central library massacre.
- You love that scene.
- I'm compromising.
Since when? You're letting this
girl mess up your mind.
- It's not about the girl.
- Then what's your fucking problem?
Living in this jungle
for the past five months.
- What, we haven't?
- You're just moving numbers around.
I'm dealing with sets and extras
and fucking explosions...
Big explosions, man.
My last movie had
12 people in it. 12 total.
Billy, it's going great.
You're killing it.
It's killing me, suit.
I'm melting down.
It's this humidity.
I can't think in this humidity.
- And I need to think.
- You got to finish.
- I can't.
- Yes, you can, all right?
And we can't without you,
so snap out of it.
I'm here.
I'll do whatever you need me to do.
You really care, huh, suit?
Yeah, I do.
You know, you've never given me
a compliment before.
I never knew you needed one.
I do.
And I need help with the ending.
Please.
It was a nice moment.
Who would have thought
Billy would be so insecure?
So I took care of it.
I personally think
it was about the girl.
But either way,
E got him to step out of it.
I was the guy with her.
I only got a hand job.
But don't tell Billy.
I'm still hoping
to get into the last scene.
Drama? No shot.
No shot, but please
bust out a polygraph machine.
So we're all set?
Oh, that's great.
That's great, thank you very much.
Everyone!
We got Stephen Gaghan
to rewrite our ending.
Stephen fucking Gaghan.
They got Steve fucking Gaghan?
Stephen Gaghan?
Awesome.
Damn, I'd love to hear
his words coming out of my mouth.
So we fedexed Stephen
a check and a plane ticket.
I was excited.
The guys seemed really passionate.
I couldn't stop thinking about what
I was gonna tell stephen
about what I was thinking.
All night I couldn't sleep.
I started writing some ideas down.
And I wrote and wrote and wrote.
I was into it, you know?
On the plane,
my ideas were flowing.
You never know if you're going
to match up with a director.
I woke up this morning
sitting at my typewriter.
I had written all night.
He rewrote the whole fucking script.
- Billy, I love it.
It's perfect.
Hey boys, I'm excited to get into this.
Did we pay this guy yet?
- Billy walsh, our director.
- Steve.
$275,000 down the drain.
But I have to admit, the script is good.
- No, it's great.
- It is great.
And Gaghan was kind enough to read it
and agree before he headed back home.
- Thank you so much.
- Hey, no problem.
I've had people read
my work and not like it,
but I've never
had anybody pay me not to work.
It was nice, actually.
FINAL DAY OF PRODUCTION (del vo)
All right, this is our last shot.
Probably the most complicated
of the whole shoot.
And I'm not in it, which is nice.
Which is why we're both
a little toasty right now.
- What?
- You're gonna have to edit that out.
So Eric, what's this scene?
Okay, the army storms Pablo's hideout.
Explosions go off
in the south, east and west.
We have nine cameras
pointed at everything Billy wants.
We've been prepping
this for three months. It has to work.
- We can't do it twice.
- Okay, are you ready for this?
Are we fucking ready?!
Nobody sounds fucking ready.
Hey, get that fucking camera off me.
I'll throw it in the water.
He's nervous.
Looks like he has it under control.
You freaking?
A little bit.
- It's all good, Billy.
- Everything is prepared.
If we get this shot, guys,
we got the whole movie in the can.
Let's do it.
Let's do it!
Roll cameras!
Set!
We're ready.
Let's kill this motherfucker! (del vo)
Cut!
The start was off, suit.
I'm gonna need another one.
I'm fucking with you.
It was perfect!
- Guys, we did it.
- Yes, we did.
Who would have thought
some kids from Queens could have?
But we did,
and it's gonna be fucking amazing.
I've never felt so good about a movie
after it was done than this one.
I know it.
You think you made a good film?
I'll tell you this:
it's either going to be genius or it's
going to fucking suck.
Until I see the first cut,
I have no idea.
But you know what?
Neither does anybody else.